<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The case of Thomas Earl of Pembroke.</title>
            <author>Pembroke, Thomas Herbert, Earl of, 1656-1733.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 6KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 1 1-bit group-IV TIFF page image.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B18728</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99887505</idno>
  <idno type="VID">190481</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2240882168</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing C1184B</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Interim Tract Supplement Guide L.R.305.a.7.[22]</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R227779</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">ocm99887505</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-99887505e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B18728)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 190481)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books; Tract supplement ; C21:2[82])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The case of Thomas Earl of Pembroke.</title>
                  <author>Pembroke, Thomas Herbert, Earl of, 1656-1733.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.).   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London? :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1700?]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Imprint from Wing CD-ROM, 1996.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="topical_term">Real property --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="topical_term">Estates (Law) --  Cases --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="topical_term">Land tenure --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03 </date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-09 </date>
            <label>Simon Charles </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-09 </date>
            <label>Simon Charles</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="statement">
            <pb facs="tcp:190481:1"/>
            <head>The Case of Thomas Earl of Pembroke.</head>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">E</seg>ARL <hi>WILLIAM</hi> being Brother of the half Blood to the late Earl <hi>Philip,</hi> and the now Earl. <hi>Thomas,</hi> and seised in fee of several Mannors and Lands, to the intent his Estate should go with the Honour, and not be severed from it by discent to his right Heir, and looking upon the late Earl <hi>Philip</hi> to be an ill Husband, gave ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>press direction to the person whom he intrusted to draw his Will, to make his said Brother but Tenant for Life, with Remainders to his Issue Male, so as his said Brother should have no power to alter the Estate, with Remainder to his Brother now Earl <hi>Thomas.</hi> AND when he published his Will, he understood his Brother <hi>Philip</hi> would THEREBY be but Tenant for Life: And it was so Declared by the person who drew it, and so understood by several Persons then present: But by the unskilful and loose penning of the Will in Constructi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on of Law, Earl <hi>Philip</hi> was THEREBY made Tenant in Tail, contrary to the express Will and Direction of Earl <hi>William,</hi> subject nevertheless to the payment of Earl <hi>William</hi>'s Debts, which was not discovered till after Earl <hi>William</hi>'s Death.</p>
            <p>EARL <hi>PHILIP</hi> becoming thus seised of his Brothers Estate, and likewise seised of several Mannors, whereof the Reversion was in the Crown, by Grant from the Crown, in Order to pay the Debts of Earl <hi>William,</hi> and to preserve Earl <hi>William</hi>'s Estate to go with the Honor, did apply himself to his late Majesty, to have the Reversion of the Mannor and Park of <hi>Ramsbury,</hi> in <hi>Com. Wilts,</hi> granted to him, (being the least profitable part of the Estate) out of the Crown, in oder to make Sale thereof for payment of his Brother's Debts; And to Induce his Majesty to grant him the Reversion, did promise to Settle as much of the Lands Devised to him by Earl <hi>William</hi>'s Will, in Recompence thereof to go along with the Honor.</p>
            <p>AFTER the Sale of <hi>Ramsbury,</hi> and part of the Purchase Money applied towards the payment of Earl <hi>William</hi>'s Debts, and the residue disposed of by Earl <hi>Philip,</hi> Earl <hi>Philip</hi> suffered Recoveries of several parts of the Estate, whereof he had a power by the mispenning of Earl <hi>William</hi>'s Will and thereby became Tenant in Fee-Simple.</p>
            <p>TO inable Earl <hi>Philip</hi> to suffer such Recoveries, the Executors of Earl <hi>William</hi> in breach of the Trust reposed in them, convey<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed those Lands to Earl <hi>Philip,</hi> before the Debts of Earl <hi>William</hi> were paid; Whereas by the Will they were not to settle the Estate upon Earl <hi>Philip,</hi> and after upon Earl <hi>Thomas,</hi> till after the Debts paid.</p>
            <p>☞ EARL <hi>PHILIP</hi> being thus seised in Fee, did frequenly in his Life-time declare his firm Resolution of settling his Estate to go with the Honor, according to the intention of his Brother Earl <hi>William,</hi> and his own promise to his Majesty: And that his Daugh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter should have only 10000 <hi>l.</hi> which was her Mothers Portion, but not his Lands,</p>
            <p>AND in pursuance of such his constant Resolutions about Four days before his Death, did order one of his Officers to send for his Council to make his Settlement or Will to that purpose, then also using some Expressions that his Daughter should have no part of his Estate, only her Mothers Portion: But the person employed to send for his Council not looking upon the Earl to be near his Death, neglected to send for his Council: And so Earl <hi>Philip</hi> was suddenly surprised with Death, without any Will or Settlement according to his Intentions. WHERBBY several parts of the Estate did descend upon his Daughter an Infant, and will be severed from the Honor, contrary to the true intent and meaning of Earl <hi>William,</hi> and Earl <hi>Philip.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>EARL <hi>THOMAS</hi> since the late Earls Death, hath paid some Hundreds of pounds of Earl <hi>William</hi>'s Debts. The Welch Estate stands charged with 8000 <hi>l.</hi> to the Sisters of Earl <hi>Thomas,</hi> and 500 <hi>l. per annum</hi> to Earl <hi>Thomas</hi> for Life, and 1500 <hi>l. per annum</hi> to the Countess Dowager of <hi>Pembroke,</hi> Relict of Earl <hi>Philip,</hi> which amount Annually to near the whole profits of that Estate. AND several of the Lands lying in <hi>Wiltstire</hi> Descended to the Daughter, have so long been intermixed with the Crown Lands enjoyed to<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gether by the Family, that it is hardly possible to distinguish the one from the other, besides many Disputes have arisen, and more are likely to arise about the extent of the Recoveries suffered by Earl <hi>Philip,</hi> what Lands are comprehended within them.</p>
            <p>THE Debts of Earl <hi>Philip</hi> are many Thousand pounds, a great part of them Book Debts to Tradesmen, in the payment whereof the Honor of the Family will be greatly concerned: And yet cannot be paid without the Aid of an Act of Parliament.</p>
            <p>THESE things alledged by the Earl, will be made out by many Witnesses.</p>
            <p>WHICH when done, he conceives it will appear most agreeabe to Justice and Equity, that the Estate of so antient a Family be Settled by Act of Parliament to go with the Honor, according to the direction of the Earl <hi>William,</hi> and the constant resolutions of Earl <hi>Philip,</hi> and his promise to his late Majesty, charged with the Jointure of the Countess Dowager, and Ten Thousand pounds Portion to the Lady <hi>Charlot,</hi> Daughter of Earl <hi>Philip,</hi> to be paid at her Age of Sixteen, or Day of Marriage, and 400 <hi>l. per annum</hi> for her Maintenance in the mean time, which will be more than the Estate descended to her can at present answer for her Mainte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nance: And a competent provision made for the payment of such Debts of Earl <hi>Philip,</hi> as his personal Estate will not reach to pay.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>